Previously on Friends:
Erica, are you okay?
Yeah, you know, maybe I ate too much.
I keep getting these stomachaches. They come and go, like, every few minutes.
-Oh, my God. -Relax, we'll just get her some antacids.
She doesn't have a stomachache! She's in labor!
Oh, my God!
If you think that I didn't say goodbye...
...because you don't mean as much to me as everybody else, you're wrong.
It's because you mean more to me.
-Rach! -What?
Hey.
Go back to sleep. I have to go home.
Oh, God. This was amazing.
It really was.
You've learned some new moves.
Yeah, well, this guy at work gave me Sex for Dummies
as a joke.
- Who's laughing now? - I am.
《老友记》第十季第十七  十八集  说再见
Breathe...
Okay. Good.
Next time, can I say "breathe"?
No. Last time, you said it like Dracula,
and it scared her.
Can I get you anything? You want some more ice chips?
No, I'm okay.
All right. I'll be right back.
- Where you going? - To use the bathroom.
- You can't leave me alone with her. - What?
This is exactly the kind of social situation...
...that I am not comfortable with.
What kind of social situation are you comfortable with?
It's just that we've never spent any time, you know, alone together.
You'll be fine.
You won't, but I'll be back in two minutes.
Okay.
So any plans for the summer?
I don't know. Maybe church camp.
May not want to mention this.
So you ever wonder which is worse?
You know, going through labor or getting kicked in the nuts?
- What? - Oh, it's just interesting.
Because no one will ever know
because no one can experience both.
One of life's great unanswerable questions.
Who knows? Maybe there's something
even more painful than those things.
Like this.
- Come in. - Morning.
- Hey. - What's that?
Oh, it's my housewarming present for Monica and Chandler.
That's a baby chick and duck.
And I named them Chick Jr. And Duck Jr.
I did not see that coming.
They'll love it at that new house.
It has that big backyard.
When they're old,
they'll go to that farm...
...that Chandler took the other chick and duck to.
- Yes. - Yeah.
It's a shame people can't visit there.
That is the rule though.
Guess what. You're almost an uncle.
What?
Erica went into labor last night.
Monica and Chandler are at the hospital right now.
- Oh, my God! - I have a feeling it's gonna be a girl.
Phoebe, you were sure Ben was gonna be a girl.
Have you seen him throw a ball?
- Is Rachel here? - I think she's still asleep.
How did it go with you guys last night?
She seemed pretty pissed at you.
We worked things out.
What's that smile?
Did something happen with you two?
Hey, I'm not one to kiss and tell.
But I'm also not one to have sex and shut up.
We totally did it.
Oh, my God. You and Rachel?
I know, it's pretty great.
So, what does that mean?
Are you guys getting back together?
Oh, I don't know.
We didn't really get to talk.
But do you want to get back together?
I don't know.
It was incredible.
I mean, it just felt so right.
When I was holding her,
I mean, I never wanted to let her go.
Know what? Yeah, I do. I want to be together.
So is she still going to Paris?
Wow, I hadn't thought of that. I hope not.
This is, like, the best day ever. Ever.
You guys might get back together.
Monica and Chandler get their baby.
There are chicks and ducks...
...in the world again.
I feel like I'm in a musical.
Morning.
Guess you'll never know how it ends.
- Hey. - Hi.
- Hi. How'd you sleep? - Good. You?
- Good. - I'll bet you did.
Would you guys mind giving us a minute?
Sure. Just keep an eye on the chick and duck.
Chick and the duck? Didn't they die--?
Dive. Yeah, they dove. Headfirst into fun on the farm.
So....
- Morning. - You too.
Last night was just wonderful.
Oh, it really was.
I woke up today with a big smile in my face.
I know, me too. It was....
You know, it was one of those things
you think is never going to happen.
And then it does,
and it's everything you want it to be.
I know. It was just....
It's just the perfect way to say goodbye.
Just a little bit more, honey.
Oh, man, this hurts!
Is it really that bad?
I think it's time to kick you in the nuts
and see which is worse.
The baby's head is crowning.
Oh, my God!
That is the most beautiful top of a head I have ever seen.
- Chandler, you have to see this. - I'm okay.
Chandler. You don't want to miss this.
This is the birth of your child.
- It's the miracle of life. - All right.
Wow, that is one disgusting miracle.
Start pushing. Here we go.
Here come the shoulders.
It's a boy.
- Is he okay? - He's just fine.
You did it.
It's a baby.
A beautiful little baby.
And some other stuff I'm gonna pretend I don't see.
- Would you like to cut the umbilical cord? - Okay.
Well, that's spongy.
Hey, handsome.
I'll love you so much that
no woman is ever gonna be good enough for you.
- We are so lucky. - I know.
He has your eyes.
I mean, I know that's not possible,
but he does.
We'll just get him cleaned up a bit.
Oh, my God, he's beautiful.
Thank you so much.
I'm really happy for you guys.
- How do you feel? - I'm tired.
You don't have that much time to relax.
The other one will be along in a minute.
I'm sorry, who should be along in a what, now?
The next baby should be along in a minute.
We only ordered one.
- You know it's twins, right? - Oh, yeah.
These are the faces of two people in the know.
I can't believe you didn't know it's twins.
This has never happened before.
Well, gosh. That makes me feel so special and good.
Wait. Did you know it was twins?
It's here in the paperwork we got from the clinic in Ohio.
- Did anybody tell you? - I don't think so.
They did mention two heartbeats,
but l thought it was just mine and the baby's.
They said, "Both heartbeats are strong."
And I thought, "Well, that's good, because I'm having a baby."
This is unbelievable.
Twins actually run in my family.
Interesting.
Can I see you for a second?
What do we do?
What do you mean, "What do we do?"
Twins!
Chandler, you're panicking.
Join me, won't you?
What do you say we keep one
and then just have an option on the other one?
- We can't split them up. - Why not?
We could give each of them half a medallion.
And then years later, they'll find each other...
...and be reunited.
I mean, that's a great day for everybody.
What if the person who adopts the other one is horrible?
What if they're not?
What if it's adopted by a king?
Yeah. Because I hear the king is looking to adopt.
Monica, we are not ready to have two babies.
That doesn't matter.
We have waited so long for this.
I don't care if it's two babies.
I don't care if it's three babies.
I don't care if the entire cast of Eight Is Enough comes out of there.
We are taking them home
because they are our children.
Okay.
- Okay. - Okay!
It looks like we're about ready over here.
Come on, Erica.
Start pushing again now.
- Here she comes. - She? It's a girl?
Yeah.
Well, now we have one of each.
And that's enough.
And then she said it was the perfect way to say goodbye.
Oh, my God. What did you say?
Nothing. What do you say to that?
You've got to tell her how you feel.
- No way. - Well, you can't just give up.
Is that what a dinosaur would do?
What?
Dude. I'm just trying to speak your language.
Ross, Rachel doesn't know that you even wanna get back together.
If she did, she might feel differently.
She might not even go.
- You really think so? - I'm telling you!
Oh, ok, this is the part of the musical
where there'd be a good, convincing song.
Hi.
Can't a girl finish a song around here?
- Hey. - Hi. I dropped Emma off at my mom's.
- Okay. - You're not taking her tonight?
No. We decided I'd set up, then my mom would bring Emma to Paris on Sunday.
Eight-hour flight with a one year old.
Good luck, Mom.
You kidding?
Eight hours with my mom talking about Atkins.
Good luck, Emma.
All right. You know what? You're right.
I should at least tell her how I feel.
- Ross. Wait, wait. - What? What?
Could you get me a muffin?
- Rachel? - Yeah?
I know you're leaving tonight,
but I just have to tell you.
I love you.
Now, I don't know if that changes your plans at all.
But I thought you should know.
Gunther.
I love you too.
Probably not in the same way.
But I do.
And when I'm in a cafe having coffee...
...or I see a man with hair brighter than the sun...
...I'll think of you.
- Bye, you guys. - Bye.
Oh, my God!
Unbelievable.
Hey, you know what might help?
I'm not getting you a muffin!
Do you think they recognize each other
from in there?
Maybe. Unless they're like people who've lived in apartments...
...next to each other for years, then one day they're pushed through a vagina...
...and they meet.
We're going to take Erica to Recovery now.
There's something that we wanted to tell you.
We decided to name the girl baby Erica.
Oh, my God, that's just like my name!
Son of a gun, it is.
Anyway, I'm gonna go get some rest.
I'm really glad I picked you guys.
You're gonna make great parents.
Even Chandler.
- Okay, well, bye. - Bye.
- We'll call you. - Okay.
Have fun at church camp.
- Look at these little bunnies. - I know.
You ready to trade?
- Okay. - Okay.
Okay. Let's see.
- We could trade later. - Yeah, I'm good.
Hey, what are you working on?
A "welcome home" sign for the baby.
How sweet! Oh, is that the baby?
No, I sat in the paint.
- Hey. - So did you talk to Rachel?
- No. And I'm not going to. - What?
Why not?
She's just gonna shoot me down.
You guys saw what happened with Gunther.
That did not look like fun.
How can you compare yourself to Gunther?
I mean, sure, he's sexy
in a more obvious way.
You have a relationship with her.
You slept together last night.
Yeah, and she still wants to go.
It's pretty clear where she is.
I know what you mean. I mean, sometimes--
- Joe. - Damn it!
If I were gonna tell her,
I don't have to do it now.
Okay? I'll be seeing her again. We've got time.
No, you don't. She's going to Paris!
She is going to meet somebody.
Do you know how many hot guys there are in Paris?
It's a city of Gunthers.
- Hey. - Hey.
What do you have there?
Oh, I made a little something.
If I had more time to work on it, it'd be better, but....
Oh, my God, you did that yourself?
Honey, that's gorgeous.
You know, the baby can't read, Mike.
Hi. You guys. The car service just got here.
I can't believe they're not home yet!
I have to catch my stupid plane.
I want to see the baby.
Monica just called from the cab.
She said they should be here any minute.
Apparently, there's some big surprise.
Yeah, did she sound happy about it?
Because my friend Ethel's baby was born
with a teeny-tiny beard.
- Welcome home. - Oh, my God.
- Oh, my gosh. - Hey.
Hey.
Hey, so, what is the big surprise?
- Oh, my God! - How did this--?
Okay, awkward question.
The hospital knows you took two, right?
Yes. It's twins.
Oh, my-- They are so cute.
Now, what kinds are they?
This is a boy. And that's a girl.
Her name is Erica.
Hey, that pregnant girl's name was Erica.
Yeah. It's a shame you two didn't get to spend more time together.
Yeah, and we named the boy Jack,
after Dad.
He's gonna be so happy.
Jack Bing. I love that.
It sounds like a '40s newspaper guy.
You know, "Jack Bing, Morning Gazette.
I'm gonna blow this story wide open."
Oh, my gosh.
So beautiful.
I want one.
Oh, yeah? Well, tell me which one.
I'll try to slip it in my coat.
Seriously.
I mean, you want to make one of those?
One? How about a whole bunch?
Really?
Yeah. We can teach them to sing,
and we could be like the von Trapp family.
Only without the Nazis.
Although that sounds kind of dull.
I can't believe this.
If I don't leave now,
I'm gonna miss my plane.
I'm so glad you got to see the babies.
Me too.
I'm just sorry I'm not gonna be around
to watch you two attempt to handle this.
All right. Oh, I can't say goodbye to you guys again.
- I love you all so much. - Love you.
- We love you. - Call us when you get there.
I will. Ross, come here.
I just want you to know...
...last night...
...I'll never forget it.
Neither will l.
All right. Now I really have to go.
Okay, au revoir.
They're gonna really hate me over there.
So you just let her go?
Yeah.
- Hey, maybe that's for the best. - Yeah?
Yeah. You know, you just-- Look, you gotta--
You gotta think about last night the way she does.
Okay? You know, maybe....
Maybe sleeping together was the perfect way to say goodbye.
Now she'll never know how he feels.
Maybe that's okay, you know?
Maybe it is better this way.
I mean, now.... Now you can move on.
I mean, you've been trying to for so long.
Maybe now that you're on different continents....
Right?
Maybe now you can actually do it, you know.
You can finally get over her.
Yeah, that's true.
Except....
I don't want to get over her.
What?
I don't. I want to be with her.
Really?
Yeah. I'm going to go after her.
Yeah, you are!
Wait! Wait! Get your coat! Get your coat!
- My coat. - This is so cool!
I have no idea what's going on,
but I am excited!
What do you think she's gonna say?
I don't know.
Even if she shoots me down,
at least I won't spend my life wondering...
...what would have happened. Where is my coat?
You didn't bring one!
My cab's downstairs.
I'll drive you to the airport.
- Wish me luck. - Hurry!
Good luck!
There's no seat belts!
That's okay. If we hit anything...
...the engine will explode,
so it's better if you're thrown from the car.
- All right, all right. Let's do this. - Okay!
- Hey! - 80th and East End.
No. I don't take passengers.
The law makes you accept any fare.
You don't understand. This cab isn't real.
What's your medallion number?
My medallion number is, get out of the cab!
- What? - Get out of the cab!
Oh, hey, can I give you guys my housewarming gift now?
- Now, that you can do. - All right.
Chick Jr.? Duck Jr.?
Don't hide from Mama!
You can open your eyes now.
- Are we off the bridge? - Yes!
Is the old woman on the bicycle still alive?
Yeah, she jumped right back up.
Oh, my God. Phoebe, slow down!
Do you want to get to Rachel in time?
Yes, but I don't want to die in your cab.
You should have thought of that before you got in!
- Tollbooth. - What?
Tollbooth!
Four bucks. There are quarters in the glove compartment.
Hurry!
Okay.
Damn, that window's clean.